<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

   <statements version="1.0" htmlParse="false">
     <statement id="1">7. Agricultural yields improved</statement>
     <statement id="2">15. The jurisdiction becomes a preferred choice for foreign investments </statement>
     <statement id="3">25. Preferential sourcing agreements are secured</statement>
     <statement id="4">23. The jurisdiction is able to sell its agricultural products with premium price</statement>
     <statement id="5">29. New plantations are allowed to expand on degraded lands</statement>
     <statement id="6">2. The cost to obtain certification is reduced</statement>
     <statement id="7">30. Business risk is reduced as it is guaranteed that the supply is "deforestation free"</statement>
     <statement id="8">26. Agricultural production systems are resilient to natural and anthropogenic disturbances</statement>
     <statement id="9">8. The landscape contains an adequate quantity and suitable configuration of  habitats to protect native biodiversity (e.g. wildlife corridors)</statement>
     <statement id="10">16. The landscape continues to provide crucial ecosystem services</statement>
     <statement id="11">1. Zero gross deforestation (conversion of natural forest cannot be offset by reforestation) is achieved</statement>
     <statement id="12">31. Zero net deforestation (conversion of forest is allowed in one area as long as an equal area is replanted elsewhere) is achieved</statement>
     <statement id="13">10. Deforestation can continue as long as the jurisdiction's commitment to forest conservation is met (e.g. Sabah state committed to 50% forest cover)</statement>
     <statement id="14">14. There is no more forest conversion for new plantations</statement>
     <statement id="15">32. Forest cover increases</statement>
     <statement id="16">9. Crop expansion on HCVs, biodiverse areas and peatland are halted</statement>
     <statement id="17">34. Reduced forest fires and haze</statement>
     <statement id="18">21. The agricultural industry supports and funds forest conservation efforts (e.g. forest restoration)</statement>
     <statement id="19">17. All stakeholders see sustainable agricultural practices as  the norm in the jurisdiction and practice them </statement>
     <statement id="20">22. Local communities adopt alternative livelihoods that do not rely on forest conversion</statement>
     <statement id="21">20. Public sector subsidies are given to incentivize activities that prioritize the JA (e.g. tax reduction for not converting forest)</statement>
     <statement id="22">3. Laws that recognize local communities rights in line with the UN Declaration on the Rights of Indigenous Peoples are adopted</statement>
     <statement id="23">18. FPIC becomes required by law in the jurisdiction</statement>
     <statement id="24">11. Governance mechanisms are in place to ensure concerted land use planning</statement>
     <statement id="25">4. The JA is institutionalized within formal governance structure</statement>
     <statement id="26">6. A clear land-use map on where future development can take place and areas for conservation should be located is adopted and translated into law</statement>
     <statement id="27">12. Increased income for local communities</statement>
     <statement id="28">35. Increased capacities for local communities (e.g  use of smart agriculture practices)</statement>
     <statement id="29">27. Local communities have sustainable and equitable access to critical natural resource stocks (e.g. clean water)</statement>
     <statement id="30">33. Local communities are resilient towards changing commodity prices</statement>
     <statement id="31">13. Land tenure rights of local communities are clarified</statement>
     <statement id="32">28. Complaints and conflicts by the local communities are resolved through an open, transparent and consultative process</statement>
     <statement id="33">19. Child labor in plantation abolished</statement>
     <statement id="34">24. Labor and living conditions of plantation workers  improve (e.g. safer working environment, etc)</statement>
     <statement id="35">5. Forced and bonded labor in plantations abolished</statement>
   </statements>